PROVINCIAL CITY OF MILS
I don't see any weapons on you.
You a mercenary?
Came to make it big by answering the
call to conquer the ruins, huh?
Yes, though I've never been
to such a flourishing town before.
Milza was a good hike for me.
It's not Milza. It's Mils.
Good grief, this is the problem
with country bumpkins.
Hey, we can let him pass, yeah?
The marquis wants us to let in as many
mercenaries headed for the ruins as possible.
You're good, so move it along.
Thank you very much. I'll do my best.
No patdowns or luggage checks.
They're surprisingly lax.
Things are going smoothly.
A private room?
We do have them,
but they're 2,000 maca a night.
He's not looking upon me favorably.
Oh, maybe it's because...
I had a long journey, so my clothes
have gotten rather dirty.
I'd appreciate it if you have anything
to wear and know where I could wash up.
Yes, yes!
Understood!
Let me show you right away!
Talk about turning on a dime.
By the way, may I ask your name?
It's Hati Skoll.
THE WOMAN KNOWN AS THE PRINCESS KNIGHT
I don't see anyone acting
suspicious of outsiders.
Seems like a fairly safe city, too.
It has all the typical shops you'd
expect from a Western fantasy town.
I wonder if any of them sell magic items.
Is this... one of those adventurer's guilds?
That'll do for getting a lay of the land.
That's good.
The flavor is pretty rustic,
but I shouldn't underestimate
the food in this world.
Taverns are great.
Spirits run high and voices run loud.
Makes it easy to eavesdrop.
Perfect for gathering information.
The continent's loaded with monstrous
knights and armies in every nation,
so who d'ya think is the strongest?
How about the Brilliant Brigade led by the
beautiful Mad Emperor Falkendotzine?
They're famously undefeated.
But the Magnar Kingdom to the north
has the Order of the White Wolves, right?
There's also the Holy Order of the Purge
in Yonato Duchy to the west.
And our very own kingdom of Ulza
has the Order of Monster Slayers.
Still...
Yeah, the strongest in the continent
has to be the Black Dragon Knights
of the Bakoss Empire, who wiped
out the Holy Empire of Neah.
I hear their Five Dragoons alone
rival an entire army.
They've got Humanity's Strongest
and the Hero Slayer, y'know?
What man wouldn't get invested in them?
I guess we should decide our future plans.
Our top priority is connecting with someone
who can read the scroll of forbidden magic.
That means finding the Witch of Taboos
hiding in the Land of Golden-Eyed Monsters.
There's also...
the monster enhancement solution.
A way to improve Piggymaru's abilities.
Hold on...
Mils has been bustling since the marquis
called for conquest of the ruins.
Discovering a new floor always
breathes life into this place!
"How to create an enhancement solution using
powdered bone from a skeleton king."
And the skeleton king's habitat...
is the Mils Ruins!
They want those dungeon ruins cleared, huh?
Everyone, thank you all for gathering here!
I am Cred Hurkley.
You may know me as
Marquis Hurkley the connoisseur.
We've recently uncovered a new floor
here in the Mils Ruins.
Now I'd like to task you with exploring it.
Whosoever obtains the Dragon Eye
Chalice sleeping within the ruins
shall be awarded 300 gold pieces!
Whoa!
I'll also pay good money
for any other treasure you bring back.
You're free to use any monster
materials you obtain as you wish!
Good. Sounds like I can keep bone powder
from the skeleton king.
We'll now begin the registration process.
Those participating, line up over here!
You can hide your face, but I can still tell!
You're incredibly beautiful.
Plus, you're brimming with grace.
Surely you must be someone of renown, hmm?
Excuse me?
Even your voice is superb, isn't it?
It's almost like...
you're the paladin captain
of a certain nation!
Seras Ashrain from the Holy Empire of Neah?
That former knight captain
with a bounty on her head?
She's an elven knight captain, right?
A former knight captain?
To tell the truth, I've met her once before.
She was quite, quite the beauty.
But even though I invited her to dinner,
she treated me with great disdain!
I don't recall ever meeting you.
You took that high-and-mighty
attitude with me back then too,
brushing me off
with utter disinterest, didn't you?
However...
Thanks to that, your face has
been burned into my memory!
Along with those lewd, outrageous,
and full, ripe breasts!
Excuse me, but I think you
have the wrong person.
In that case, what about your ears?
Unlike humans,
elves all have sharply pointed ears!
However, there are very few elves
in this area around the kingdom of Ulza.
But, but, but...
As you all well know,
the former captain from a certain country
who's been on the run lately is
a high elf known as the Princess Knight!
You might fool idiots, but you can't fool me!
Those pointy ears are proof
that you're Seras Ashrain!
How do you like that?!
The one who revealed the Princess
Knight's true identity was me!
The Flash, Monk Droghetti!
Huh?
What...?
It's that woman from the forest.
I-Impossible!
A-And your face! Your face is different too!
My name is Mist Balukas.
I'm not Seras Ashrain.
Are you satisfied now?
N-No way! This can't be!
He had the wrong person
after all that fuss?
I seriously thought it was the
knight captain for a moment.
You won't get away with this!
Every last one of you beautiful women is...
I won't forget this, Mist Balukas!
Talk about unfounded resentment.
I'll need to do some
shopping before I delve.
Excuse me.
Are you here to answer
the marquis's call as well?
Kind of.
Tough break back there, huh?
It wasn't much of a problem.
Even so, you should probably be careful.
That man who harassed you was
bright red with rage and hatred.
Every now and then,
I wind up crossing people like that.
It's easier once they hate me and stay away
rather than try to get close
for my affections.
I can tell you're intentionally
trying to avoid interacting with others.
That said, I still have a request.
You want advice so you aren't swindled
when buying items to explore the ruins?
I'll pay you for your assistance.
Well, you see... Truth be told,
I am in need of travel funds.
So that's a beneficial proposal
for me as well.
Then we have an agreement?
I'm Mist Balukas.
Hati Skoll.
I see.
This woman is keen to lies.
An alias, obviously.
You and I both have our secrets,
so there's no point in sharing
our real names for now.
Agreed.
You've been a big help.
Here's the fee I promised.
This much?
By my math, you saved
me over three silver pieces.
Then I will gratefully take these silvers.
Though this is much more than I expected,
so I'm honestly hesitant to accept it.
Thank you very much.
Now then, I'll be on my way.
She's so light.
You okay?
You have bags under your eyes.
I-Indeed. I haven't slept well
for several days.
I-I'm fine, though.
Sorry to worry you.
Hmm? What next?
Naturally, we start conquering
the ruins of Mils.
MILS RUINS
It's a little ox demon!
Run!
Like a miniature version of
the minotaurs from the Ruins of Disposal?
Paralyze.
Poison.
My Paralyze and Poison both worked.
Seems the monsters from the Ruins of Disposal
had exceptionally tough hides after all.
O-Over there!
That's where we saw the
little ox demon! Please!
Sure, leave it to me.
I-It's dead...
Looks like another mercenary defeated it.
Wait, this thing isn't even injured!
No, hold on. If you look closely...
This is a dagger wound, right?
Huh?! They killed it in
one blow with a dagger?!
It wasn't a single hit from a dagger, no.
Right now, I'm not feeling any
threat from the monsters here.
Stats: Open.
Not getting much experience either.
Guess I'll move on at a brisk pace.
I know you two are strong,
so I have a request for you.
I want you to make that woman
who humiliated me in the plaza
regret ever being born.
Any specifics? You want her killed?
Yes, kill her!
Though if she begs for her life
and you decide she's truly sorry
for what she did to me,
then don't kill her quickly.
You sure are pissed at her, huh?
She seriously ticked me off!
That woman made a fool of me,
and the thought of her still breathing
and going on without a care...
It makes my gut seethe!
Makes me want to claw out my chest!
Until I see that smug face
twisted in despair as she dies,
I'll never sleep in peace!
Once you kill her, I'll feed her to them!
I'll feed that pretty face
and body to the monsters!
W-We don't care if that's how you
want to dispose of her,
but at least let us have our fun first, okay?
I could tell she had an amazing body,
even through her garb.
Of course!
Use her until she's in tatters.
She dismissed me twice.
Me! Of all people!
That woman is monster feed!
Monster feed, monster feed, monster feed!
Who the hell're you?!
You eavesdroppin' on us?
You're an irredeemable lot.
What?!
Who do you think you're talking to,
brat?! I'll kill you!
You snap way too much.
Some green brat trying
to act like a damn saint?
Let's just kill him quick. He's in the way!
It's pretty common for folks
to die in ruins, y'know?
Hold on a moment.
Huh? What's this?
I'm sorry. Please spare me.
Begging for your life the instant you
realize you're outmatched?
Too bad you can't take it back once—
Paralyze.
Wh-What?!
I can't move!
How...?
What did you do?!
Who knows?
More importantly, who were you gonna kill?
Too bad.
My own villainy makes me want to puke.
Probably because it reminds me of them.
Poison.
What?!
Exterminating guys like you
feels strangely satisfying.
It's surprisingly nice.
I won't forget this! I'll make you regret it!
Are you stupid?
That's exactly why I'm stomping
you out here and now.
Seems you're the ones becoming monster feed.
I guess I'll hit the new floor
if I go one more down.
I'd like to take a break
before setting foot into it.
It is what it is. I'll backtrack a bit.
About three hours of sleep, huh?
Thanks for keeping a lookout.
What's the matter?
THE SABER TIGERS
- There's something unprecedented
happening in these ruins right now.
There's something unprecedented
Monsters are dying
in strange ways in random places.
- They are?
- Yeah.
FOSSE, SABER TIGER VICE CAPTAIN
- The funny thing is we can't
figure out what's killing them.
The funny thing is we can't
We just know their skin turns deathly pale.
CAPTAIN LILY ADAMANTINE
- Both strong and weak monsters alike
are falling in this strange manner.
Both strong and weak monsters alike
Even the monsters on floor 14,
which we were the first to reach.
As the leader of the Saber Tigers,
I value my comrades above all else.
It's regrettable, but we're pulling out now.
Do you want to return
to the surface with us?
No, though I'm grateful for the offer.
I see.
Well, if you see any of the other mercs,
do us a favor and pass along the news.
I will.
Now then, I should get moving.
Yeah, that's right.
They probably mean the corpses
of monsters I killed with my skill.
If word of the unusual situation spreads,
it'll mean fewer mercenaries.
This might be a lucky break for me.
Is that the Dragon Eye Chalice?
I'll bet this thing moves.
Anyone familiar with fiction
from modern Japan could anticipate that.
Paralyze.
Poison.
Piggymaru, can I ask you to keep watch?
So, this thing is the prized item
of this event?
Sure is pretty.
Now, what should we do?
It's you?
WANDERING WARRIOR MIST BALUKAS
- I thought I would be the first one here
with the other mercenaries pulling out.
I thought I would be the first one here
I guess I lost my chance taking a rest
after some trouble with a pack of monsters.
If you need this, I'll let you have it.
Huh? What did you just say?
If you want it, it's yours.
Wh-What do you want in return?
Three hundred gold is...
There's nothing I really want.
I-I cannot besmirch my honor like that.
You're in a hurry, right?
Though you should be getting proper sleep.
You look like you could
collapse at any moment.
Later.
Please wait.
I simply cannot take this and offer nothing.
Hati Skoll is just a sickeningly sweet guy.
He's also kind to boot.
Especially to beautiful women.
Y-You're lying!
That's an awful accusation.
I'm sorry. It's just...
My objective isn't that treasure.
It's a monster lurking below.
I thought only the floors leading up
to this chalice had been discovered...
There's a monster that has
something I need right now.
It just so happened that the call to conquer
the ruins coincided with my time here.
If that's why you're here,
this does make more sense, but...
No, in that case, Sir Hati,
would you please allow me
to at least guard you?
What?
All I can really offer right now
is my skill with this sword.
I swear to you that I won't be a hindrance.
Will you accept?
M-My apologies.
However, I cannot just accept
the Dragon Eye Chalice for free.
- However, I cannot just accept
- No sign of her relenting.
However, I cannot just accept
the Dragon Eye Chalice for free.
She must feel strongly
about repaying her debts.
So what should I do?
Can I add a few conditions?
Yes.
As a rule of thumb, we avoid questions prying
into each other's circumstances.
We're just a bodyguard and client.
Understood.
Also, I won't necessarily return
to the surface within the day.
So if you want to return on your own,
I won't be responsible for you.
If that's okay, it's nice working with you.
Thank you very much.
I shall protect you, Sir Hati,
even if it costs me my life.
That was splendid work.
Thank you.
What is it?
Well, I wanted to ask you about something.
About monsters with golden
eyes and those without.
Oh, of course.
Monsters with golden eyes are said
to hold a great deal of "experience,"
and they're recognized as the perfect prey
for heroes from another world to "level up."
Are you familiar with the concept
of otherworld heroes?
I am.
Apparently they gain no experience
from killing other people.
I hear experience points
are a feature unique to monsters.
Explains why I got nothing from those guys.
And how are monsters
without golden eyes regarded?
They're regular monsters.
Some are capable of forming
positive relationships with humans.
I see.
According to legend, the demon king,
who is the root of all evil,
radiates a special energy
known as demon king essence.
Monsters strongly influenced
by it turn golden-eyed.
It unleashes the instinct for violence
that all monsters harbor.
Golden-eyed monsters...
Gold... A golden hero...
That golden hue is a sign.
That's a little ominous.
I sense the presence of a monster.
A monster?
It's not strong, so I paid it no mind,
but I keep sensing it.
It's very close by.
Piggymaru.
This is Piggymaru.
Long story short, we're partners.
I hope you two will get along.
Go ahead.
Are you sure it's safe?
I'm Mist Balukas.
It's a pleasure to meet you,
Sir Piggymaru.
It's a very cute slime.
It's oddly comforting.
Let's take a break here.
You can get some light sleep.
I'll wake you when it's time to leave.
No, I'm fine.
Would you at least lie down for a while?
It won't do me any good if you
collapse partway through.
Very well.
I'll at least lie down, then.
Piggymaru.
Sir Piggymaru?
Sleep.
There, now she should be
able to get some rest.
I'd guessed as much.
But you really are the former
knight captain of Holy Neah...
Seras Ashrain, huh?
Looks like their corpses were eaten by
monsters, but I guess this means it's true.
Four Holy Watchers were killed here
in the blink of an eye
without any real sign of battle.
Who could do this to such skilled men?
Seras Ashrain, with her Spirit Regalia.
CIVIT GARTLAND
HUMANITY'S STRONGEST
- Will you provide me with some excitement?
THE CHAIN KNOWN AS TRUST